JULIO ALCANTARA

Location – Dublin, Ireland **Telephone** – (+353) 089 964 1510

Email – <u>alcantara.juliosousa@gmail.com</u>
GitHub – <u>https://github.com/julioalcantara</u>
LinkedIn – www.linkedin.com/in/julio-alcantara

PERSONAL PROFILE

BSc Honours Degree recent graduated in Information Technology at CCT Dublin. Experience in Java, C++, MERN stack, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 and. **Open for graduate positions**. As both a team player and having the ability to lead, I embrace new challenges with continual learning, growth and a can-do attitude.

KEY SKILLS

- LANGUAGES: Java (SE 6), C++, JavaScript (ES6), HTML5, CSS3;
- LIBRARIES & FRAMEWORKS: jQuery, Bootstrap, Node, MongoDB, Express, React, React Native;
- TOOLS: Git & GitHub, Command Line, Postman, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator;
- Languages Fluent English | Native Portuguese:

EDUCATION & TRAINING

2019 – 2020 BSc Hons in Information Technology (Level 8)

CCT Dublin - Ireland

Modules: Mobile Application, Multi-Paradigm Programming & Scripting, Network Management & High

Availability, Strategic Business.

Project: Mobile Application – FINAL PROJECT (Sep/2019 - present)

- Individual project, responsible for developing a full-Stack booking system application for tattoo artists and tattoo shops;
- The app is using the JavaScript library (React Native);
- Database design and its implementation is required for this project development;
- Technologies: React Native, Node.js, Express, Firebase, MongoDB;
- Link for the Project: https://github.com/julioalcantara/tgs.git

2016 – 2019 Bachelor of Science in Computing & Multimedia (Level 7)

Dorset College, Dublin Ireland

Modules: Computer Programming Fundamentals, Computer Programming, Databases, Mobile Applications,

Software Engineering, Multimedia Programming.

Project: Mobile Application – FINAL PROJECT (Sep/2018 – May/2019)

- Individual project, responsible for developing a social media for a tattoo artists and tattoo shop.
- The app was built in Android Studio;
- Database design and its implementation is required for this project development;
- Technologies: Java, Firebase
- Link for the Project: https://github.com/julioalcantara/TattooGuestSpot.git

2013 Certificate (Advanced) in Industrial Production Facilities

SENAI - National Service of Industrial Training - Minas Gerais, Brazil

Modules: Project management, electronics, mechanics, technical drawing/diagram.

ADDITIONAL ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE:

Student Tutor and Class Representative (Oct/2019 - present)

- Supporting the lecturer during the class, monitoring students, dealing with queries or any difficulties regarding computer science subjects and explaining technical topics.
- Meeting with faculty members, NStep National Student Engagement Programme.
- Completed training through the college to be a Class Representative.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

While studying full-time for my Degree in IT, I have been working part-time as a Web Developer and Social Media Manger in order to gain skills and fund my college fees and living expenses in Dublin.

02/2018 - Present DCL Ecobuild Ltd, Dublin - Voodoo Ink - https://www.voodooinkstudio.com/

Position:

Part-time Web Developer / Social Media Manager

- Develop & design website for company profile, review SEO, UX/ UI Analytics & curate visual content
- Maintain, create & update social media platforms as Facebook/Instagram including the creation of promoted campaigns. @voodooinktattoodublin / voodoo ink tattoo studio.
- Increase Company's digital exposure, expand organic digital following & develop weekly newsletters
- Liaise with manager & marketing team regarding graphics for studios branded promotional printouts

2014 – 2015 Position:

Sartori Servicos, Minas Gerais – Brazil Mechanical Technician

- Maintained & monitored metal material structures & insured daily primary risk analysis (PRA)
- Managed team & dispensed blueprint tasks amongst employees to optimize efficient workflow
- Created weekly PowerPoint presentations to present to supervisor responsible for that particular sector in order improve quality control that met with industry standards
- Co-ordinated team meetings with management to discuss daily & weekly tasks, projects & deadlines

2013 – 2014 Position:

Somasa Industria e Commercio, Minas Gerais – Brazil **Industrial Mechanic**

- Liaised with Area Supervisor regarding maintenance trouble reports & equipment quality control
- Prepared & executed project tasks with emphasis on equipment safety that met company regulations
- Managed daily technical drawings, created & dispensed projects to team members in order of priority
- Repaired engines & associated metal components in sequence with team for safety assurance

2011 - 2013

Gerdau, Minas Gerais - Brazil

Position:

Electromechanical Assistant

- Operated & maintained electromechanical equipment to meet company & consumer expectations
- Accessed diagrams & technical orders to determine methods & sequence of team assembly
- Analysed, recorded & prepared written testing documentation for Project & Area Manager approval
- Verified dimensions of parts to ensure project specifications, using precision measuring instruments

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

On-line Learning

2020 / in progress
2020 Complete React Developer in 2020 / Udemy / 39.5 Hours – hyperlink to course
2020 Complete React Native + Hooks / Udemy / 57 Hours – hyperlink to course
2019 Advanced JavaScript / Udemy / 25 Hours – hyperlink to course
2019 Introduction to JavaScript / Alura Cursos / 20 Hours – hyperlink to course
2019 HTML5 & CCS3 (1 to 4) / Alura Cursos / 32 Hours – hyperlink to course

Other:

Category A/B Irish Driving License.

REFERENCE AVAILABLE.